Gianni DePaola

C

216-375-9234

gdepaola1@outlook.com



OH 44233

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Proactive IT Security Analyst with a solid track record at Union Home Mortgage, enhancing network security and developing robust incident response strategies. Expert in SIEM and Microsoft Office 365 security, demonstrating exceptional leadership and meticulous attention to detail. Recognized for substantial improvements in safeguarding digital assets and elevating system integrity.

SKILLS

Operating Systems: Windows, macOS, Linux (Kali and Ubuntu)

Microsoft Office 365 Admin Portals (Entra, Intune, Defender, Purview, EAC)

Leadership

Identity and Access Management

Security Policy Development

SIEM (Security Onion)

Network Security

Attention to Detail

Team Collaboration

EXPERIENCE

JR. IT SECURITY ANALYST, Strongsville, US

Union Home Mortgage, May 2023-Present

- Assisted in the development of an incident response plan outlining procedures for handling security incidents.
- Conducted security audits on systems, networks, applications, and databases to identify potential threats.
- Monitored network traffic for malicious activities, such as intrusions or denial-of-service attacks.
 Provided security assessments of IT infrastructure, identifying and mitigating risks and vulnerabilities.
- Configured firewalls and other access control measures according to organizational standards and best practices.
- Analyzed system logs to detect suspicious activity, identified the root cause of incidents, and recommended corrective actions.
- Performed vulnerability scans using automated tools to detect weaknesses in the organization's systems.
- Recommended changes to security posture to reduce emerging threats to environment.

INTERN, IT SECURITY, Strongsville

Union Home Mortgage, May 2022-May 2023

- Investigated suspicious activity or possessions to safeguard assets and protect employees and customer data
- Modified computer security files to incorporate new software, correct errors and change individual access status
- Documented computer security and emergency measures policies, procedures and tests

- Encrypted data transmissions and erected firewalls to conceal confidential information as it was being transmitted and to keep out tainted digital transfers
- Trained users and promote security awareness to boost system security and improve server and network efficiency
- Reviewed violations of computer security procedures and discuss procedures with violators to keep violations from being repeated.

INTERN, IT SERVICE DESK, Strongsville

Union Home Mortgage, August 2021-May 2022

- Consult and assist with standard software and hardware issues
- Strong knowledgebase on Microsoft Suites Office 365, Exchange, Azure, AD
- Extensive knowledge and assistance with mortgage based software such as Encompass
- Basic troubleshooting assistance to 1000+ company members
- Providing standard IT service desk skills and internal customer service.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN CYBERSECURITY AND COMPUTER NETWORKING, Cincinnati, OH

University of Cincinnati (UC), January 2005

CERTIFICATIONS

- IBM Cybersecurity Practitioner
- IBM Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner
- IQ4 The Threat Within

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Theta Chi Fraternity Fundraising Chair

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

VOLUNTEER, Strongsville, OH

Union Home Mortgage Foundation, June 2022-June 2022

Assisted rangers in clearing out invasive cattail plants in the Cleveland Metroparks.